hey everyone welcome back to another
interesting lesson in this tosar
automation playlist today we are going
to talk about the web tables which is a
very favorite topic whenever you start
working with any UI
automation now talking about web tables
and web tables are generally dynamic in
nature which means the values uh inside
the cells keeps on changing now how do
you keep track of these changes uh is
there a way to maybe compare a web table
with a baseline okay so whenever you
have a web table uh so as per
requirements you set up a baseline which
means uh the values inside the table are
consistent okay uh as per the
requirements and then uh when you get
that kind of result you set that as a
baseline for your remaining executions
right
so in tosa um there is an option to
basically do a comparison of different
Baseline for your web tables okay so
once you set a particular Baseline uh
for a particular web table you can do a
number of execution cycles for that web
table and then uh it can compare your
current state of the web table which
means the current values in the web
table with the particular Baseline which
you have set earlier okay and if they
are different then you will get the
result as failed and showing you what
has changed in your web table now this
is a very useful way of comparing your
web tables depending on how the values
are changing and this could be very
useful uh when you have to test a
streaming application which means a lot
of data is coming into the tables from a
different source and then you need to
continuously compare large tables with
large number of rows and values okay so
let's see um how this can be done for
this I already have a module called
select price option and I have already
added um the object which is the table
right now um we are going to work on
this particular test case which is
compare table Baseline and then I'm
going to drag this module in here so
that we at the table here with all the
rows and
columns okay um so how to set a baseline
for your web table right so select the
web table go to the test cases section
and the last option you will see is for
creating a new Baseline okay now there
are two ways of creating a baseline one
is the manual way and one is the
automatic way so let's first look at the
manual way so uh you go and select the
web table and then click on create base
Baseline okay so what it will do is tosa
will now try to set a baseline uh where
it will compare um the table which is
currently open in your application it
will set all the values and it will
create a baseline for this particular
web table okay and if it is successful
uh you will see that the Baseline was
successfully created okay for this
particular table which is table also
here you will see that in the value
there is a table compare expression
which is Set uh and the action mode is
set to verify okay and then uh there is
also a baseline created under the price
table and you will see that when it was
created at what time it was created
okay now um also what you can do is so
what if you want to uh ignore some of
the values which is present or ignore
some of the rows so you don't want to
include them in the comparison you want
to exclude them so a row like select
option right because these are uh just
the radio buttons and we don't want to
include them in the comparison so what
you can do you can come here and then uh
in the row okay I'm going to type it
here called the select option okay
and then uh when you type that uh it
will automatically set the action mode
to exclude okay because uh this is under
the Baseline table comparison and
whenever you are selecting any
particular row uh you want to exclude
that now you can also do that based on
the cell value okay so if you want to to
exclude based on some cell value if the
table is dynamic then you can do it at
row level or column level uh and then
you can also set some value like if uh
the cell contains limited or um the
column is platinum so whatever condition
you want uh to exclude whichever row or
column you can set that accordingly
right here okay so this is a way to
exclude any particular row or column
from the comparison okay and now uh we
have successfully created a baseline for
our web table and this will act like an
expected result for your web table so
every time the comparison will happen
against this particular values now what
we also want to do is we want to execute
it multiple times so that we can compare
our web table with the Baseline okay so
here I have created a execution list and
there is uh a select price option
execution list under that I'm going to
now drag my particular test
case okay and uh here now uh if I can
execute this particular execution list
okay so now um there are no changes in
the web table currently so my execution
should ideally pass it is trying to
compare the current state of my web
table against a baseline version okay so
now you will see that uh the test case
will pass and in the results you will
see that it is comparing against a
Baseline and the verification was
successful okay now uh let's do some
changes in our application so what I'm
going to do is uh in the ENT product
data instead of insurance sum I'm going
to to select something else here okay
and then when I go back to price option
the prices per year would increase and
also some of the other options right so
now the web table has changed now uh if
I come here and uh now if I run this
again this time you will see that it
will
fail okay so now you can see uh the
second execution failed because the web
table has changed okay and uh here you
will see U the details so verification
has failed and the column uh was
modified right this was the expected
this was the actual and uh this was
column and row one was modified so it is
going to give you all the details of
what has changed and you can also see
that in the screenshot now this can be
compared in two different ways you can
compare the values or you can even
compare the structure of the web table
right so if the structure of the web
table changes and that feels in a
comparison you can raise a defect for
your development team to fix it so it's
a very easy way of comparing your web
tables whether something has changed
from the Baseline version
right so now there are two executions
one past and one field what you can also
do is uh if you want to set a new
Baseline you can do it directly from the
execution list okay so here if I select
this uh test case and in the execution
list section on the top you will see
there is an update Baseline okay so if
you want to update the Baseline of your
web table you can do it right from here
okay so select the test keys and then
click on update Baseline and you will
see that the Baseline opiz table
successfully updated to snapshot from
this okay so if uh you want to change it
now you can change it right from here
and this will be your new basine so the
next execution that it will will be
compared with the new Baseline not with
the existing Baseline okay so this way
you can update your Baseline
even so this is the manual way of
creating a baseline updating the
Baseline and then looking at the
comparison results by executing it from
the execution list now what if you want
tosa to do it automatically
automatically set a baseline right so
that can also be done by going to file
settings and then uh under tbox uh under
engines there is table compare okay and
then in table compare this is the enable
autogenerate Baseline and this can be uh
set to True okay which means uh
automatic generation of BAS lines will
be enabled okay so every time you
execute automatic Baseline will be
created for
you okay but um I would keep it false um
I would rather prefer the manual way of
creating a Baseline and then updating
the Baseline if
required so this way you can compare
different web tables against a
particular Baseline and you can make
sure that your web tables are not
getting affected by any particular
development change which is happening
especially to the structure or to
certain values which you don't expect to
change now for the values which you
expect to change or which are dynamic in
nature you can just ignore it from the
comparison okay by excluding that
particular row or column uh totally from
the comparison so this comparision can
only be done for things which you don't
expect to change from the Baseline
version which was said
earlier that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next video